Sopheap Roath Kuch

(971) 246-4265 Sopheap.Roath.Kuch@gmail.com

Technical Skills:

Focused on enterprise computing technical support. Highly adaptable to learning new server-side and client-side operating systems, applications navigation and user interface, with use of word processing, spreadsheets, and various programs in office productivity.

Personal and In-The-Field Skills:

Specialized in troubleshooting and problem solving through the utilization of internet research and technical documentation to remediate technical issues.

Freelance Personal Computer Technician (1997 to present date) – Custom hardware installs; Attended software installs; Customer support; Repair; Consultations, Troubleshooting, Windows and Linux OS command-line/terminal experience; and Configuration of networks with basic routers via: LAN, WAN, and WI-FI/wireless.

Certifications:

CompTIA A+ - Since June 2012. Renewed in June 30, 2016. Expires June 30, 2019 - COMP001020411140 Will renew in January 2020.

Achievements:

Completed enterprise-level upgrades of Windows Server 2008 to 2016 and 2019 in October 2018-2019. Completed client-side workstation upgrade from Windows 7 to Windows 10 in July 2017.

Successful migration of Office 2010, 2013, 2016 to Office 365 in January 2017.

Transplanted IT backbone and equipment in relocation project in February 2016.

Implementation of learning lab for SharePoint 2013 in May 2014

Upgraded testing center systems to new hardware and software requirement in April 2013.

Experience:

TriVium Systems, Inc.

October 2017 - December 2019

Client Services Engineer

- Tier 1 Technical Support Frontline Customer Support Manage all client and server machines with remote-based support, triage, troubleshooting, implementation, installation, client training regarding specific software deployed.
- The primary role is to receive and handle daily inbound technical support calls. Contact and create relationships with customers and vendors. Create and manage support tickets through Sugar CRM ticketing system.
- Troubleshoot customer technical issues and assist in product knowledge and applying customized deployment of software products regarding company call recording engine and call analyzing tool.

- Investigate and gather information, and diagnose\ fix\ escalate\ confirm application interconnectivity issues as it relates to specific installation environment at the network level and
 associated telecom systems. Supported Linux CentOS, and Microsoft Windows 7, 8, 8.1, and 10
 Client and Server 2008, 2008 R2, 2012, 2012 R2, 2016, and 2019 Deployments. Performed
 backups and migrations of SQL Server 2008, 2012, and 2016. Worked with configuration of
 Office365, POP/IMAP and SMTP servers and email protocols.
- Manipulate SQL database information and confirm \ solve application inter-connectivity issues.
- Manage and stage servers and PC workstations equipment and test recording hardware.
- Help facilitate the migration process when decommissioning hardware and software reaching end of life support. Fabrication of proprietary network tapping equipment.
- Repaired corrupted installation and deployed new software on new systems.
- Supported customers with user interface interactions and trained new users on how to utilize software capabilities.
- Manage tear down of staged systems after in-house configuration completed and burn-in testing validated setup prior to shipment of customer equipment and server\workstation turnkey systems.

New Horizons Computer Learning Centers of Portland Information Technology Manager December 2011 – August 2017

December 2015 – August 2017

- In charge of day-to-day IT operations. Oversee three departments Sales, Faculty, and Operations that are utilizing computers and related software.
- Point of contact regarding IT planning and infrastructure changes. Administrative reporting to operations and corporate IT department.
- Direct equipment, hardware and software, purchase and deployment, installation, and maintenance.
- Manage client-end, sales, and back-end equipment setup and maintenance. Led system upgrade, migration, security hardening.
- Implement theft prevention; and conduct software and hardware inventory prior to yearly budget requests.
- Manage IT interns and IT support staff. Set tasks, coordinate short-term projects, and supervise training of critical operational procedures.

New Horizons Computer Learning Centers of Portland Operations & Facilities Supervisor

December 2013 – December 2017

- (Acting Operations Manager) Ensure classroom scheduling are accurate and maintain website listing and pricing consistency with other production based databases.
- Facilitate training and guidance of systems usage with sales department and all employees.

New Horizons Computer Learning Centers of Portland Information Technology Support Administrator

March 2012 – December 2013

Primarily supported Microsoft Windows 7, 8, 8.1, and 10 Client and Server 2008, 2008 R2, 2012,
 2012 R2 Deployment, including server room, network and media cabling care and setting up and

- configuration of testing center equipment; System Configuration and Maintenance; Client System Troubleshooting; and System Image Management Capture and Restoration.
- Administrative work included account creation for new employees and manage logistics of onsite classroom delivery off campus.
- Worked with Corporate IT Department to ensure policy and procedures are adhered to.
- Secondary support for Corporate IT Help-desk and close troubleshooting tickets. Information Technology Intern – December 2011 – March 2012
- Help Desk and Operations Support.
- Customer service with students to troubleshoot issue(s) with using location equipment as it pertains to class participation.

Tosoh Quartz, Inc.

July 2008 – September 2008

Manufacturing Technician I

- Operation of CNC mill and lathe
- CNC machine cleaning and maintenance
- Follow tolerance standards
- Adherence to and execute offsetting of tool wear
- Perform data entry for parts via work orders

Education:

DeVry University, Keller Graduate School of Management Completed MS Degree Master of Information Systems Management, Concentration: Network Applications

University of Phoenix, Online
MAED/TED - Master of Elementary Education

Portland State University Completed BS Degree

Bachelor of Science – Major: Organismal Biology, and Minor: Psychology